Imam Abubakar Olusola

+234 913 795 0366 | ideacloudng@gmail.com | GitHub

ABOUT ME

Highly skilled blockchain developer with over 5 years experience in the tech space working mostly as a full stack web developer. I have had the opportunity to work in various tech areas such as Fintech, Blockchain, and Management systems. Driven to solve problems through intense research–driven processes that turn business innovations into practical solutions through development. I am currently developing for the future of the Internet.

EXPERIENCE

IdeaCloud Nigeria, Lagos, Nigeria — Lead Developer

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

- I design and develop static portfolio websites for small brands and businesses.
- I developed a dynamic web application for a food delivery business.
- My team worked on program flow and research for projects.
- I coordinated a team of designers and developers to work on a project launch from start to finish.

Google(TensorFlow.js), Remote — Campus Influencer(Volunteer)

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

- I create content for the promotion of the use of TensorFlow.js in the local developer community.
- I develop small machine learning projects to teach students on how to use TensorFlow.js in their web Projects.
- I am currently developing a facial recognition web app to facilitate enhanced security on websites.

University of Ilorin COMSIT, Kwara, Nigeria — Full Stack Developer(Intern)

NOVEMBER 2021 - MAY 2022

• I coordinated a small team of developers and designers to build a web-based employee management system for institutions.

SKILLS

Problem-solving
Strong communication skills
Team player and leader
Great working speed
Great learning speed

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

Languages Solidity, JavaScript, PHP

Markup/Design HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Bulma CSS

Frameworks

React.js, React Native, Next.js, Node.js, Hardhat, Truffle, Laravel, Tensorflow.js

Database/CMS MySQL, MongoDB, SanityCMS, GraphCMS

TechnologiesGraphQL, Rapid API,
Alchemy, Moralis, Ethers.js,
Web3.js

RECENT WORK

Visit my GitHub Repo here

- I designed and developed a podcast web application and rendered it as a PWA.
- I analyzed and fixed database errors on the University's Bursary Automation System.
- I managed contents and documents on the University's website

Freelancer.com, Remote — Blockchain Developer(freelance) (Formerly Full Stack Web Developer)

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

- I work on gigs like design of wordpress themes and static web pages.
- I work on gigs like development of web applications, including PWAs and APIs.

CERTIFICATION

CODEDAMN

Certificate of Completion: Solidity 30-day Challenge

BRAINY CODELAB

Software Developer Certificate (Web)

EDUCATION

University of Ilorin, Kwara, Nigeria — B.Sc. Computer Science

DECEMBER 2018 - OCTOBER 2022 (IN-VIEW)

SOCIAL LINKS

Twitter

Click **here** to visit

LinkedIn

Click here to visit

Dev

Click **here** to visit

Instagram

Click <u>here</u> to visit